<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to motivate your employees!]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 23:52:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Run Your Business like a Cult]]></title><description><![CDATA[How is the Great Resignation impacting your company today? Are you able to at least keep up with customer demand? Although, this isn’t a bad…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/run-your-business-like-a-cult/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/run-your-business-like-a-cult/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;How is the Great Resignation impacting your company today?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you able to at least keep up with customer demand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, this isn’t a bad problem to have per se, you’ve gotta admit that it sucks not being able to grow or motivate your teams as you’d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like countless other small business owners and management ppl, you’re probably suffering from many of the day to day, and week-to-week issues that’s plaguing a whole generation of right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quitters, lack of quality applications, mistakes on the job that end up costing more than money sometimes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen, I get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s only so much you and your team can do at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, so you BELIEVE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, what if I told you about how to catalyze your organizations’ growth in a way that you’ll never find in a book or a seminar or YouTube video?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, allow me pull back the curtain for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s post is about creating beliefs and managing them for the purpose of propelling your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about running your business LIKE a CULT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ DUN DUN DUUUUUN ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, wait. I said LIKE a cult. Don’t get all wide eyed on me…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word gets a bad rap. It’s just short for culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a hard-core sports fan, guess what? You, might be in a cult that believes so strongly in something you’re willing to actually fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workplace culture runs on the same set of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at how this all happens in simple terms and how it applies to what you’re dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;————————————————————————————————————————————————————&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALIGNMENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is everyone on your team(s) on the same page?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, most management tend to focus a lot on the routine stuff which is good and all but morale dies without a real sense of CRISIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the real secrets to motivating people. Politicians know this. Marketers know this. And now you do too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without mastering this toolset you can go ahead and keep herding cats in the dark my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or with some solid practice you can step into your power as a leader who inspires action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BELONGING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money motivates people to a LIMITED extent. After all, it’s easy to find another fire to put out at another company. Especially when everyone is desperately hiring like right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do so many bosses miss the boat when it comes to keeping talent long term?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, a couple things actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If management wants turnover rates to drop like a sack of potatoes all they need to practice is deep acknowledgement upon their people for the efforts put forth. Even if its for small stuff. It shows you care and that they are not just a cog in the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, run your cult-like business on the factor of employee-growth. Really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure out how to make your company a growth academy of some kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll never have people breaking their backs for food and shelter ever again, you’ll have people breaking their backs to build a castle with joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COMMUNICATION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If people aren’t talking about the above two factors then they might as well not exist. Along with your potential business growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you speak to your people is the glue that holds it all together, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t think so much about talking to your teams to seem cool. Most of it is crap. I could tell you stories here…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get better at communicating naturally, you’ve gotta master LISTENING.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t listen. So won’t your employees. Guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[No One Wants to Work Anymore]]></title><description><![CDATA[‘It Is What it Is’ Happy Monday everyone! I hope you had a great weekend and arrested for the week. Today I wanted to talk about how…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/No-One-Wants-to-Work/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/No-One-Wants-to-Work/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:01:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;‘It Is What it Is’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Monday everyone! I hope you had a great weekend and arrested for the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to talk about how language affects performance in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now everybody who speaks English is heard the phrase. Nobody wants to work anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s about as cliche as it is what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(How absurd? How judgmental and).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you but I cringe when I hear these types of things.
Look at who you’ve heard. Say these quips over the past year or two.
Heck maybe your one as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m willing to bet. Lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does language have an effect on performance in the workplace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to notice is how we let statements like these above. Get baked into our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like staring at a light bulb for a few minutes and then all you can see is this blacked out blur that takes 10 minutes to get rid of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there anything wrong with statements like these above?
Well negative attitudes are very normalized and most workplace culture. And the effect of this on performance looks like dragging feet and poor communication, unusual and easily avoidable mistakes that cost time and money and strip morale from the daily ins and outs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, maybe this seems like the cost of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like any organism in the wild, your best bet is to adapt or die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These times call for a new kind of leadership that most organizations don’t even know how to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so much of what I’m pointing at here has to do with communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So whether or not you think it’s right or wrong to normalize statements like these above, just take into consideration that in a way the statements kill possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their statements so loaded with bias and resignation. It’s like putting your flower in the microwave on high when you hear it everyday these statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s certainly nothing wrong with venting, however, if you’re really committed to business growth and the ability to supercharge your people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I’ve got to tell you you’re going to need a new way to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it all starts with attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you communicate as a leader dictates how your employees will communicate in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is usually in the conversation when I joke that there are no such thing as bad children or employees. There are only leaders and parents who need improvement. Lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I invite you to really listen to not what your teammates and employees say but how they say it. Don’t do anything more than that. Just listen. And consider that how communication is happening in your organization is literally sapping your profits.
Listen like a doctor for a heart. Palpitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen like a startled mother hearing her child swear for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you want to gain some serious mastery on how to drain the drama from your workplace then I recommend you sign up for my weekly email where I go into a deep dive with instructions on how to take this listening of language to another level.
There will certainly be a training available for this module of the honeymaker way as it is quite interactive and takes hours of practice.
Again, it’s like staring into a light bulb. It doesn’t take very long for this stuff to get baked into our heads. So that everywhere we go we see differently.
And so.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Keeping the Quitters]]></title><description><![CDATA[Even if you’d rather let them go Everybody knows someone who’s a quitter. Whether they’ve seen it at work as an employee or a boss. Working…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Keeping-the-Quitters/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Keeping-the-Quitters/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Even if you’d rather let them go&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody knows someone who’s a quitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether they’ve seen it at work as an employee or a boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the restaurant industry in New York City. It was easy to spot those who are thinking about quitting for about to. Hell, they’d talk to anyone except management about leaving!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I have found it to be deeply frustrating when I have somebody on my team who quits or doesn’t follow through on even a basic request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feeling of being left high and dry snubbed wondering how in the world the other person is justifying they’re crapping out on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quitters are the number one reason most ppl hate trying to put a team together for new projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I think about it, it’s not even just the quitters. It’s the people who never follow through on even basic requests that leave us feeling resigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s the truth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen small business owners and management ignore the signs that folks are about to never show up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the signs?
….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one of the surest warning signs that folks are packing their bags. Is the levels of drama or pretense between you and the other person or the person and the organization especially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active disengagement is basically pretending 9:00 to 5:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And shelling the performance with gossip circles and drama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the mass majority of typical business leaders shelf this category of quitters because they don’t know actually how to turn them around. In fact, they subconsciously believe or buy into the quitters belief so that there’s just an air of resignation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the old way? Next line…. Fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure it’s fine if you’re a business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And sure, it’s fine if you as a business leader are clear, it’s okay to let somebody go because of XY and z. If you’re like many small business leaders, turnover is expensive and inefficient, leaving your business and the difficult position to be competitive or really grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re like most business types, your experiencing touchy turnover issues and trouble attracting new blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why isn’t it in your best favor to be able to turn around the quitters and never follow through hers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t want to be an ordinary business leader who cuts their nose off spite their face, then I highly suggest you follow my recommendation below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The factor that you can leverage to turn around this category of team member is communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication so that the other party feels safe and will be authentic. Even if they’re so sure that they don’t want to quit or follow through on a project because of other circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication butdtst the bubble of pretending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just in case it’s not obvious yet, I’m not talking about chit chat. I’m talking about a structure for regularly checking in with people, especially if you don’t have a lot of time to spend knowing what’s going on and everybody’s world with a 50 plus employee company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to master how to turn around quitters and never follow through hers. Sign up for my weekly email where I dive into the topic and give you the structure to try for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to start practicing powerful check-in conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go be on. Simply asking how’s it going or small talk?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improvise a short conversation that might last five to seven minutes tops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get curious about what’s happening and their world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask for feedback about their experience or ideas about day-to-day operations. For instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And before you leave the conversation and this is really important. While you’re still present with the person. Listen for how to align what the person’s dealing with with what your business stands for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can, create a sense of opportunity with the other person before walking away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And keep track on your own terms. What everybody is dealing with personally and how to keep a sense of opportunity alive with unique requests and powerful check-in conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an employee is an alignment with a business or organization, there is practically unlimited energy and focus. When there is a sense of belonging, an employee will be loyal and honest. And when there is powerful communication goals you never imagined will be possibly accomplished!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abc ABC.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>